[Music]
hello everyone and welcome to my home my
name is paola i live here in the pacific
northwest in a rural cottage surrounded
by forests and public lands
few people live here and there are a lot
of mountains all around sometimes that
get closed off during the winter
it is indisputably a beautiful place i
wouldn't want to be anywhere else but
nowhere is perfect
i love all the seasons each is stunning
in its own way but winter offers
something quite different from the
others
this time of year has a unique set of
challenges
many of them you can guess in regards to
dealing with so much snow and freezing
cold temperatures
[Music]
oh
january often finds many experiencing
cabin fever
even though i love pursuing my creative
hobbies and doors i miss being able to
traipse through the forest barefoot with
the ease of the springtime
especially when it's negative 15 and
being outdoors can feel so painful and
risk frostbite
i've always had fairly poor circulation
in my fingers and toes and so i need to
be quite careful this time of year
during the very cold snaps
this week had blizzards and i found
myself for the most part stuck at home
longer than i wished
snow plows were delayed and rural roads
stayed untouched for longer than usual
and sometimes it was quite dangerous to
drive and my electricity went in and out
i am used to this so don't get me wrong
i love to watch shows and movies and
read books as much as the next creative
but after a while without being able to
go back to my normal routine
things started getting a bit old
[Music]
i found myself for the first time this
season understandably and temporarily
feeling a bit lonely a bit bored and out
of spirits
i know this is a relatable feeling i
think a lot of people feel those winter
blues especially after the holidays when
things get very cold i think we often
associate feelings like this as
something we need to cure or see as
negative and i understand
though i do think sometimes these
feelings can be a wonderful opportunity
to learn about ourselves
and to assert that self-control and
believe that
this too shall pass
this week i definitely felt a bit low
i've had so much family visiting over
the holidays and saying goodbye to my
sister was hard as i rarely get to see
her i really do enjoy my time alone and
need it every day to recharge
but it's funny how your feelings
surprise you sometimes
[Music]
i am a great believer in distracting
myself when needed so i got busy
cleaning the house reorganizing things
and creating a very lovely and cozy
atmosphere that made me fall in love
again with my home life
i do know that i've deeply needed some
time alone to recharge so even though i
don't feel as well as i do usually i am
embracing this time
i love doing practical little things
that make my life easier over the next
several weeks
in this case finishing a much needed
project for my wedding
we needed to make tapers and jar candles
and thankfully i got some help from my
fiance he could finally visit so we
enjoyed a lovely evening together
[Music]
hello everyone i am sorry in advance i
i'm tired i'm so tired
i don't know i just didn't sleep well
last night so
anyway hopefully that um does not affect
my voice
so many people kind of experience the
blues this time of year i think
especially if you're in an area
that has so much snow
so
anyway i have kind of used it as an
opportunity to just you know get all
those little things done around the
house that i've been meaning to do and
really create a cozy atmosphere that
that makes me feel very welcomed and at
peace so that i've time to recharge it
was a wonderful december i received many
many socks
as gifts
so i also got a rechargeable hand warmer
which um was really important i struggle
a lot with keeping my
toes and fingers
warm
this time of year i put on gloves and i
use the hot packs and i do everything
but still sometimes it can just get so
cold when it's in the negatives negative
10 negative 12 15 it you know it really
affects me and i guess i just have poor
circulation but um yeah anyway it's it's
always a bit tricky this time of year i
do
find that once you know chill veins set
in i really need to stay inside for a
little bit until you know my
extremities start to heal yeah so i've
been uh reading a lot i've been trying
out some spooky stories i read coraline
last a couple weeks ago and i'm now
reading a brand new book that's a
collection of ghost stories which i'm
quickly realizing is a horrible mistake
i usually don't like scary stories i'm
very afraid very easily you know but um
i don't know why i just decided i should
try out books like that because i never
read books like that and so far i'm i'm
a big wimp the other thing i've been
doing a lot is lighting a lot of candles
even more than usual i found some
beeswax candles at my
specialty store recently and i just
really like these one is in the shape of
a pinecone and one looks like a
just
whimsical
old
winter fairy in my opinion he's just
the cutest little wisest looking guy and
i just really like it they are
definitely too pretty to burn as you
guys know i really enjoyed the mythology
candle company and i bought some candles
for my family who are also all readers
and all love fantasy and fairy tales and
that's what the can candles are inspired
by i purchased three candles for
december but then they sent me three
more which was really kind of them
it was very very sweet and unexpected
the camelot collection which was really
exciting because not only i enjoy the
arthurian legends but my sister grew up
just obsessed with king arthur and
camelot and all those amazing legends so
i'm definitely reserving one of the
candles for her anyway i have slowly
become more and more obsessed with
candle collecting i don't know what's
happening it's definitely
unnecessary but i find myself with more
candles all the time and it's wonderful
um it's definitely becoming
a little bit of a
hobby to try out new candles so i've
been having a lot of fun it's it's such
a
simple kind of silly thing but it's
brought me a lot of joy i really love
when my cottage smells really nice
especially when you have a dog that
loves to run around outside and roll and
pretty much anything smelly he can find
it's really nice to just let candles and
kind of cleanse the space a little bit
anyway i am enjoying it this time i
actually do hope that
the snow will
stop soon so that i can get out a little
more and it's a little easier to drive i
am definitely a nervous driver so i
don't like to drive if it is too much
snow or too icy especially because there
are a lot of wild animals here and you
have to be very careful on the roads
anyway i hope you all have a wonderful
day i'm gonna go
take a nap i am
so tired
i don't know what's going on
um anyway
i'm sending my love and i wish you all
the best goodbye